welcome to this video in the last video
I created on webpack I showed you how
you could add HTML and images to your
workflow so how you can get web pack to
copy your HTML file basically and some
of you asked if I could also show how
you could work with multiple HTML files
there are actually two great solutions
for that
now there are more solutions and you can
simply Google to find more but here are
my two favorite solutions I will use the
same plugin we used before the HTML web
pack plug-in in one of the two solutions
and the average solution I will use the
file loader to copy the HTML file so
let's have a look at about solutions now
I want to start with the HTML web pack
plug-in but for both solutions I
actually need an additional HTML file
right now I get my index.html file here
in the source folder and to keep it
simple I will simply add a second one
which it will name users dot HTML now
whatever name you like of course now
this file exists in this folder too
obviously and now of course I want to be
able to well visit this file in the end
so do you copy it into the dist folder
which we create I now need to go to my
website conflict or chess file and when
using the HTML web pack plug-in a very
simple way of using multiple HTML files
is to simply duplicate this plug-in call
here so I'll simply add a new one in
there like this and I here of course I
point to the users dot HTML file of
course this has downsides that you need
to know which HTML files you use at the
point of time you create your config so
it's not a very dynamic approach if
you've got an app here where you add one
or thousand HTML files then this might
not be the approach you're looking for
but if you have for example just the
index.html file and then a 404 HTML file
to handle such errors there's my PD
approach you are looking for now of
course if I just drop in a line like
this what this plug-in would do is it
would still create only one index.html
file and simply use users HTML as the
template now since it comes second here
so that of course is not the behavior
one so I will give these files created
by the plug-in explicit file names I can
do this by adding the file name or
configuration or option here and we
could name this first one index.html
which is the name of the file you want
to copy and I'll keep the volume of the
second file too
so name this users HTML of course you
could rename it to something else here
now with this setup here you can now run
npm run build to start your web tag dev
server again and if you now with it
localhost 8080 you see the index.html
file we created in the last video and
now if we wizard users HTML well we
don't see anything here but this error
which I guess makes sense because what
happens the HTML plug-in here
copies the user's HTML file creates the
users HTML file which we do find if this
would not be the case so if we try to
find a file which doesn't exist we get
this error here so we do find the file
but in the file if we have a look at the
Dom let me increase this you see that it
still tries to import our bundle and
that is just what the HTML plug-in does
it does not just copy a file it also
injects your bundle into it that's the
idea behind this template now what you
can do here is you can add the chunks
options at this to an empty array let me
restart this server here and I will
reload this page and now you see we
don't get an error here in the console
because now we also don't try to import
this because what's the chunks option on
this plug-in you can define which chunks
you will which build artifacts so to say
should be injected into that edgy HTML
file so for the first one index.html if
we go back to that page you see it's
still injected everything because there
we don't specify chunks but here since
we set chunks to an empty our
it doesn't check anything now just to
complete the picture with these chunks
so now we use an empty array to tell it
well don't add any chunks what is a
chunk now if you would want to tell it
hey please include our bundle chairs
file here again we would need to define
entry a bit differently we could write
it as a JavaScript object here and set
app for example that's just the one
possibility you can choose any property
name you like here and now this would be
our app junk everything which is created
from this entry point here and then we
could define app here as a string and
now if I restart this server and we
wizard our users HTML file again and I
reload this you now see we get the error
again because now it injects this bundle
again so that is how we can control this
with chunks and how we overall with
chunks and the file name at the second
web peg plug-in call here can make sure
that we just copy that file again the
limitation of this approach clearly is
that we have to know which files we have
at the point of time we write this
configuration here and that might not be
the case for our setup so I will leave
it like this but there is only one
option we do have another one now for
this other option or comment out this
plug-in call a leaf to change on the
first one doesn't matter if we
explicitly named it index.html that
would have been the name anyways but now
I want to load that HTML files
differently from within our code so
let's say we don't know it at the point
of time we write our configuration but
certainly at the point of time we write
our app so then we could say we want to
load our users HTML file and I will
actually go in my app dot J's file
remember that it is in this file where
we also load our F CSS code so we're not
limited to including JavaScript here we
can also include other assets of which
you want to make web pega where
basically so what we can do here is we
can also import our HTML file so we
could say import and now go up one level
then not en excuse me the users HTML
file like this now that looks super
strange but this will actually work as
you will see so now I'm importing that
but of course web peg doesn't know how
to handle this so let's go to the web
peg config and here I will copy my rule
I created four images
we'll simply add it below there and here
I want to check for HTML files and you
could of course also change this
expression to also to take HTM files
so that's HTML and I'm going to use the
file loader I want to keep name and
extension but the output path it should
just be slash and the public path
therefore to which I don't need to
specify so actually we can omit the
output pop to now what's the file load
rule setup I need to tweak it a little
bit though I need to add exclude to make
sure that I don't also copy the
index.html file because what we have to
keep in mind here is that we do include
the index.html file into our web pack
build process right we do that here so I
need to exclude it and this actually
takes an absolute path so I'll use pop
resolve again your name and now we're
then in the source folder and then we
take the index.html file so don't want
to include this in my rule whoops should
be without that slasher down so with
this if we now restart and people run
build with this exclude thing edit your
overall HTML rule it should work that if
we now visit our page and I reload here
in XHTML still works
and if we go to users HTML it seems to
find this file and let's now finally add
at least some content to it make this
maybe an HTML page users page and most
importantly let's add something here
into our h1 tag let's save this and
reload the page and we see the user's
page so this is now working and this is
how you could copy multiple HTML files
either by using the HTML web pack
plug-in if you know how many files it's
going to be at the point of time you
write
conflict you set up your workflow or
using the more dynamic solution where
the name port here is imported up here
and then the file loader now if you
search for it you'll find more and
different solutions may be solutions
which better fit your use case but that
would be two ways of doing it